# Software Engineer

## Alex Cummaudo

+61 0420 553 685 alexcu@me.com http://alexcu.me

#### Summary

With industry experience in the education, research and commercial sectors in software engineering, teaching and design positions, I'm currently employed as an iOS developer at SEEK.com.au, Australia's largest jobseeker and careers website.

I discover creative solutions to problems unsolved and envision seamlessness in products that enrich people's lives, connect us together and help us grow as individuals.

#### Skills

## **Core Strengths**

Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, RESTful API Development, Concurrent Program Design, Teaching, UI/UX Design and Prototyping, Website Administration

#### **Technical Skills**

AngularJS, Node.js, iOS/Objective-C/Swift, JavaScript/CoffeeScript/DOM, SCSS/LESS/CSS3, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, ET;X, C#/.NET, C/C++, Pascal

#### **Software**

Git, AWS, Apache2, Nginx, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Xcode, Xamarin, Coda 2, Trello, Pixelmator, Lucidchart

## Experience

## iOS Developer

Aug 2015-Present

SEEK Ltd., Melbourne

SEEK is Australia's largest jobs, employment, career and recruitment website.

- Development on SEEK's iPhone and iPad app, contributing additions such as personal job recommendations and App Store reviews onto the mobile platform.
- Improve search relevance ranking tools to help candidates find more relevant jobs and improve the quality of SEEK's search algorithms.
- Deployment to the cloud via AWS and Docker.
- Experience with continuous deployment and test-driven development environments.

#### **Software Engineer**

Aug 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne NICTA Software Innovation Lab (SSIL), Hawthorn

SSIL delivers research-driven high-impact software solutions and is partnered with NICTA.

- Lead drone-flight software project that automates drone flights without human intervention.
- Developed fleet visualiser prototype integrated using Google Maps SDK used for bus fleets in Kuala Lumpur.
- Created a web-based IDE used for rapid prototyping software to create Android applications using a custom DSL.
- Implemented redesign of SSIL's website.
- Development with bleeding-edge technology stacks and rapid-prototyping environment.

## **Introduction to Programming Tutor**

Mar 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn Teaching a first-year introductory programming unit.

reacting a first-year introductory programming unit.

- Engagingly teaching students to learn foundation programming concepts
- Group discussion and running group exercises
- · Preparing students for future programming and problem-solving units
- Helping students through basic Pascal and C
- Giving one-to-one feedback.

## **Web Application Developer (Pro Brono)**

Winter Break-2014

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

Development of a lightweight modern Learning Management System, Doubtfire.

- Building a large-scale web application utilised in tutoring position for student progress tracking (http://doubtfire.ict.swin.edu.au)
- Developing front-end development with Bootstrap and AngularJS
- Back-end development using Ruby on Rails, PostGres and Grape API

#### UI/UX Developer

Mar 2014-Aug 2014

LeadSoftware, Melbourne

LeadSoftware specialises in complete tracking, logistic and dispatch systems.

- Lead UX and UI design for large-scale on-board taxi dispatch system and iOS/Android apps in development for CABiT, a Melbourne-based Taxi company
- Strong interaction with development team to explain prototypes and mock-ups developed and provide feedback on implemented designs
- Iterative prototype process using a mix of whiteboard, Pixelmator, Keynote and FluidUI

## **Programming Help Desk Staff**

Aug 2013-Dec 2013

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

Providing assistance in out-of-class sessions with students.

- Assisting students learn syntax of C, Pascal, PHP, JavaScript
- · Explaining programming concepts to students and working through logic problems in a enthusiastic and approachable environment
- Help Desk initiative and staff commended by the Australian Computer Society

#### Education

## **Bachelor of Science (Professional Software Development)**

Aug 2013-Present

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

High Distinction Average (GPA 4.0). Perfect marks of 100 in Introductory and and Object-Oriented Programming units; near-perfect marks of 98 in iOS Development and Usability.

#### **Key Disciplines:**

- Web and iOS Application Design and Development
- Concurrent Programming
- · Data Structure Theory
- Development of Programming Languages
- User Interface and Experience Design
- Database Design and Programming

### **Victorian Certificate of Education (VCE)**

Feb 2010-Nov 2012

Parade College, Bundoora

Australian Tertiary Admittance Ranking (ATAR) of 98.00 of 99.95.

## Awards

## **Certificate of Achievement Awards**

**November 2014, July 2015** 

Highest Achieving Student with the highest marks in nine subjects

Awarded by Prof. John Wilson - Executive Dean, Faculty of Science, Engineering and Technology, Swinburne University.

## Certificate of Appreciation Award

1 Nov 2013

Swinburne ICT Student Ambassador Program

Awarded by Prof. Leon Sterling - Dean, Faculty of ICT, Swinburne University.

## Vice Chancellor's Scholarship

31 Mar 2013

On outstanding academic excellence Awarded by Prof. Linda Kristjanson - Vice Chancellor, Swinburne University.

**Dux Award** 8 Feb 2013

On achieving excellent VCE results and attaining one of the highest ATAR scores in the college. Awarded by Dr. Denis Moore - Principal, Parade College.

## Extra Curricular

## University

- Member of the Swinburne Tinkerers Guild
- Open Day Volunteering—discussing and advocating Swinburne degrees
- Spokesperson for Swinburne's Faculty of Information Technology
- Mentor for VCE students enrolled in Swinburne's Higher Education Studies within the VCE program

## **Hobbies and interests**

- · Hiking and jogging
- Antique computing
- Casual indie game developer at Paperbox Studios

## Referrals

Dr. Rajesh Vasa Head of R&D Swinburne Software Innovation Lab +61 435 016 006 rvasa@swin.edu.au

Dr. Andrew Cain Senior Lecturer Swinburne University +61 03 9214 5324 acain@swin.edu.au

Mr. Robert Wagstaff iOS Developer SEEK Ltd. +61 413 468 930 robwagstaff1984@gmail.com